Elias Touil

elias.touil@gmail.com | GitHub

Summary

9 years of experience full stack software developer with design abilities equipped to deeply understand users and business while overcoming technical hurdles. I seek honorable and adventurous collaborators uncovering their full potential and helping others flourish.

Skills

Full Stack: TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Next.js, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma, TypeORM, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Tailwind CSS, Chakra-UI, Material UI (MUI), Vercel, Heroku, GitHub actions, Husky.

Design: User Interface Design (UI), User Experience Research, User Experience Design (UX), Usability Testing, Wireframing, Prototyping, Graphic Design, Figma, Photoshop, SVG. **Startups:** Grant Writing, Value Proposition Design, Pitch Deck Design, Photography, Video.

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Spark Jam (Saas Startup Cofounder)

June 2023 - Dec 2023

- Designed and developed an audience engagement app for content creators, acquiring 2,500
 users in its first month using Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Prisma, PostgreSQL, and Vercel
- Established a continuous feedback loop by monitoring users with Google Analytics, and Microsoft Clarity, and running usability tests with early adopters
- Introduced Scrum and documented procedures utilizing ClickUp to clarify the technical workflow for non-technical stakeholders
- Onboarded an engineer and documented the code to a successful responsibility transfer

Lead Developer and Designer, La Maison Jaune (Saas Startup Founder)

2019 - 2023

- Conceived a digital museum guide by leading a team of 3 augmenting 55k museum visits using Next.js, TypeScript, Apollo, GraphQL, Chakra-UI, PostgreSQL, and Heroku, tripling visitors' adoption compared to the previous native museum app
- Single-handedly built a prototype using Preact, pitched and secured Canada's largest art museum as an early collaborator two weeks after the idea's inception
- Brought image recognition and 3D to the browser, conducted user experience tests to improve on friction points, doubling education content engagement among museum visitors
- Recruited three software engineers and managed collaboration with outsourcing firms using agile and scrum to increase development speed and meet clients' demands
- Engineered a continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipeline across multiple instances utilizing Git, Heroku, and Bash streamlining individual contributions
- Authored and submitted successful grant proposals, securing \$160K in funding and \$25K in sponsorships from government and incubators, enabling key developmental milestones
- Produced promotional and sales visual assets, leading teams of up to 8, to ensure visibility and demonstrability of product on the web and at industry events

Metryx (Saas Startup)

- Re-designed branding, user experience, and user interface of a data-intensive workforce management tool using Django, React.js and MUI, positioning the product as the modern option and reducing most paths to action by 30%
- Proposed new frontend patterns and tooling, coached offshore developers on using data visualization and calendar tools to improve development speed and code quality

DevCyclop (Agency)

• Improved user interface and readability of data-intensive bid planning platform for large construction enterprise using vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS

My Touch (Startup)

• Created a request for proposal and organized a bidding process for a cosmetic e-commerce platform and warehouse management system

Venue Genie (Saas Startup)

• Realized mockups for the Airbnb of venues using React.js

Let's Hub (Startup)

- Transformed in-person orientation games and tools into web-based applications, empowering low-skilled workers to demonstrate their value to future employers
- Defined new visual identity by conceptualizing and coding a design system with CSS and SVG

Various clients

• Designed and realized dynamic websites using Python, JavaScript, Django, SQLite, Contentful, WordPress, Shopify, Liquid, React.js, Gatsby, CSS, and Sass.

Commercial Photographer, Freelance

2008 - 2022

 Created visuals enhancing the image of renowned brands, including Air Miles, Canada Space Agency, IGA, Cadillac Fairview, Place-des-arts, Canada Parks, British American Tobacco

Volunteering

Board Member, Cosimu

2019 - Present

- Co-wrote app requirements, and business and innovation objectives with C.E.O.
- Developed visually unique and complex sound controllers for music learning apps in React and CSS to demonstrate a transition to the web and increase cross-platform compatibility

Mentor, Academos (Career orientation office hours)

2021 - Present

Mentor, Brébeuf HX (Hackathon)

2023

Education

B.Sc.A Computer Sciences (Partial)	, Université du Québec à Montréal
------------------------------------	-----------------------------------

2015 - 2016

B.Sc. Psychology (Partial), Université de Montréal

2010 - 2012